## **ABOUT ME**

I am a well-rounded Python developer with over 5 years of experience in data science and web development teams. I believe in building things right, building the right things, and working in a sustainable way. That means caring about code quality and testing, releasing small and iterating, practicing open communication and always reflecting on my processes. Looking for a new position where I can make a difference.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

# Senior Software Engineer (self-employed), London/remote

Delivering data science, data engineering, GIS and backend projects. Selected experience:

- Backend and systems engineer at the Link Institute for Market Research.
- Project leader at the Open Humans Foundation. Responsible for integrating Google Fit as a data source.
- GIS expert for Deutsche Welle. Consulted on article about the originating locations of fires in recent years.
- Data journalism project: Is London a forest?

March 2017 - August 2018

# Senior Software Engineer at siroop, Zürich

Worked in the data science and the web development team of a Swiss e-commerce platform with thousands of sales every day.

#### Full Stack Web development

- Built critical features from scratch (voucher and promotion support, custom brand pages, integration of analytics tracking) using Django, Flask and RESTful services
- Extended existing functionality (product pages, CMS service and payment system) practicing TDD and pair programming
- Optimized test running time, local deployments with dockercompose and other aspects of the day to day development process
- Updated and deployed new AWS infrastructure (lambdas, Kinesis stream, DynamoDB) using Terraform
- Participated and led agile ceremonies (stand-ups, retrospectives)
- Acted as deputy team lead for a team of 7 and mentored more junior engineers

#### **Data Engineering**

- Launched personalized product recommendations to production
- Worked closely with data scientists to build a tool library
- Introduced and set up airflow as a pipeline manager for the recurring jobs
- Introduced and set up databricks as a development environment
- Did troubleshooting for scaling and cluster issues the data scientists faced (pySpark and pandas)

◎ Ariadni-Karolina Alexiou☆ 17 Bessemer Place, London SE

+44 73 83 001 288□ carolinegr@gmail.com

http://www.github.com/carolinux

# WORK EXPERIENCE CONTD.

November 2015 - February 2017

# Lead Data Engineer at Tracktics GmbH, Zürich

Responsible for overseeing the extracting of insights from GPS and sensor data, collected from a tracker worn by football players in the field.

- Built the production data pipeline. It automatically processed the raw data (various stages, eg: MATLAB binary, Jupyter notebooks and python modules, chained together with celery)
- Launched various additional tools (heatmap generator, football pitch locator) to production
- Designed and oversaw the collection of test data to evaluate our algorithms
- Built evaluation into the data pipeline (in a way that externals could use it, and internals could easily create new report templates for new metrics)
- Built a library of common functionality together with the data scientists and mentored junior engineers

**SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2015** 

# Software Engineer at Teralytics AG, Zürich

Worked as a software engineer, extracting insights from mobile phone data and supporting my colleagues to do so.

- Created data pipelines to go from raw data to automatically updating web dashboards in production
- Created interactive visualizations of geospatial data (using PostGIS, d3, QGIS) for our customers
- Contributed to (and became co-maintainer) of an open source tool to visualize geotemporal data
- Built a library to unify access to diverse data sources

### SELECTED CONFERENCES AND ARTICLES

- 2017 Speaker at PyData Berlin conference: Patterns for Collaboration between Data Scientists and Software Engineers
- video | article

  2016 Published reflections on the future of Data Pipelines and the future of Python for Data Science
- 2015 Tutorial (Python): Exploring a UFO sightings dataset
- 2015 Article: Common mistakes with Python and Big Data
- 2015 Workshop on visualizing geotemporal data
- 2014 Presented published paper at VLDB 2014
- 2014 Speaker at PyData Berlin conference on Mall Analytics (from prototype to product)

#### **EDUCATION**

2011 - 2013 **Master of Science** 

COMPUTER SCIENCE ETH Zürich

GPA: 5.5/6 (also received scholarship)

2007 - 2011 Bachelor of Science

COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Athens

GPA: 9.3/10 - Top graduate in fall 2011

# SELECTED FREELANCE OR OTHER WORK

# Node Developer for SignedBlock, Athens

Extended and dockerized a program for live collection of data from the cryptocurrency market.

#### QGIS Plugin Developer for OpenGis.ch, Zürich

Responsible for developing Python plugins for geospatial data management.

#### Python and Data Engineering Tutor, online

Micro-consulting via codementor.io on several data science/engineering projects.

#### Mentor at Andela, online

Mentored junior programmers in Python, testing and programming patterns to prepare them for working remotely.

#### Data Consultant for New Incentives, Zürich

Created a data pipeline in Scala to sync data daily across mobile devices and Google spreadsheets.

# Software Engineering Intern, Google Zürich

Migrated a feature of Youtube Analytics to the new backend.

#### LANGUAGES

English, German and Spanish in full professional capacity. Greek as mother tongue, some French.

#### Personal Interests

Painting (have some professional training), Social Science, Traveling. I have combined my thinking/practice as a programmer with those of being an artist to create a Drawing for Techies Workshop, which I have run multiple times in Switzerland, Germany and the UK.